In high school and in college, I
definitely was not naturally gifted. In
fact, I had to come up with systems like
this on a notebook page just for me to
get by. What I didn't realize back then
it was that I was building a learning
system, one that was transferable across
disciplines including business. Now,
without ever having read a business book
or without ever graduating with a
business degree, my new business in just
15 months has done over $13 million.
How? Well, it's actually because this
learning system has transferred over to
an operating system for this
eight-figure business. In this video, I
want to do something really cool. Side
by side, I want to break down how my
academic learning system turned into
this eight-figure business operating
system and how you can start to apply
for yourself, too. Here's the truth a
lot of you don't know about me. So, you
might see the Dean's list, you might see
the bachelor's and master's in
biomedical engineering simultaneously,
but what you don't see is the amount of
struggle that I had to overcome just for
me to get by. When I first came into
biomedical engineering, I was so
intimidated. A lot of my peers were
significantly smarter than me and I
would have these classes of
thermodynamics or computational modeling
and I had no idea what the heck I was
doing. I was utilizing all these passive
learning strategies, I wasn't retaining
information very well. Even if I was
doing decently on an exam, it wasn't
compounding to the next one. So, I felt
like I was constantly starting from
scratch. And it was this exhaustion,
this burnout that made me realize I
can't keep doing this. I have to learn a
different way. So, my biomedical
engineering degrees have a
neuroengineering concentration. So, I
was familiar with the space and then I
got obsessed with cognitive psychology
and trying to understand how human
beings learn. And some of you have
actually seen me talk about this system
on this page. It is to prime and then to
have your in-class notes, post-class
immediate review, and ultimately a
revision. I want to give you the quick
version so that we all have context
before we head into the business
operating system version of it. Before I
walked into any class, I would prime.
This basically means that you are
contextualizing or getting the big
picture understanding because we as
human beings, we need linkages. So, we
need scaffoldings to build on top of in
order for new information to be retained
quicker. Then, when I was in class, I
wasn't trying to write everything that
the professor was saying. Instead, I was
actively listening and constantly trying
to test myself in real time. Right after
I would do an immediate review for about
25 minutes to consolidate the
information to ensure that there was
stickiness, to ensure that I wasn't
actually going to forget it. And then
lastly, after a few days, I would build
out a diagram. It was one of the
greatest active recall practices I could
do because I was contextualizing it not
just for it, let's say the class alone,
but for the entire curriculum if
possible. This really tests your
knowledge. If you can see how one piece
of information connects to an
overarching hierarchy of information,
that's when you can really say that
you've understood it greatly. So, those
are the four steps that I used to
survive biomedical engineering. And
here's the part that changed everything.
I never stopped using that system. I
just stopped calling it studying and it
became business. I still feel as though
priming is the most important step for
me. Even as I try to learn today,
anything in business, I will always have
pages and pages and pages printed out or
on my iPad in order for me to review
before I go into any main learning
event. Again, for me today, that could
be a podcast, it could be a production
set, it could be an investment meeting,
it could be any one of those, but before
it, to have that scaffolding. I need the
big picture. Let's take podcasting as a
very specific example of this. So,
recently I've decided to initiate this
endeavor of mine and it's been a neat
challenge because to prepare means that
you are doing a lot of work. You're
doing a lot of research. You're trying
to encapsulate somebody's entire
livelihood into a set of pages that you
can go ahead and prep for. And so, I I'm
always doing this and basically what I
do is I will write down everything from
their origin to their career, if there
was any career changes to that how
content or let's say personal branding
has influenced it because basically our
podcast is called Creator on Plugs, so
I'm trying to actually fit it into the
messaging of the podcast and my
audience. So, you have all these moving
parts and I basically just write it all
out and I'll use Claude here. So, I'll
go ahead and use Whisper first and I'll
just voice dictate everything that comes
into mind about this person. So, I'm
like already testing my knowledge. And
then I go ahead and my podcast producer
has her own notes and basically what I'm
doing there is an active recall practice
where I'm trying to recall the things
that I've researched about the person,
but I'm also testing it against what my
podcast producer has developed so that I
can see where I might have missed out or
where my podcast producer might have
missed out as well. Then I actually
utilize Claude to ask me questions about
it. So based on the brief, it'll ask me
10 questions and I'll have to understand
it, right? So I'm practicing with that
so again that I have a scaffolding, I
have an understanding of the person
generally before I go into the main
learning event. Now for this next step,
just like I said in the classroom
setting, I'm not trying to write down
everything that the professor is saying
because then I'm not actively listening.
And then I'm not just trying to also
passively agree and not along. I have to
test my knowledge while I'm trying to
learn it. That's the best way that you
can consolidate information. Here's a
really good example of this. When I
first started business, it was when I
was still actually a student and I came
out with a $39 product. Now again, I had
no context as to how to even build out a
landing page. I didn't even know what
that meant. I didn't know even how to
come up with a good name. I didn't even
know how to market it. I didn't even
know how to collect somebody's email. I
didn't know any of it. But I knew that
there was only so much I could learn by
listening to YouTube videos or trying to
read some books. I I actually kind of
ignored a lot of those steps and I said,
"Let me just go out and try." And as I
went along, my website crashed. I
realized I didn't have the right domain
or the right hosting policies involved.
And basically what had happened is that
the entire week sucked. I had all this
hype and then everything came crashing
down. What was crazy was that I for the
very first time in my life, I made my
first $10,000 and then I lost my first
$10,040 or something like that because
there was some sort of tax or some sort
of thing that was attached once the
money refunded back to them as the
website got crashed. But this is all to
say that I had a level of urgency to go
ahead and develop the new change, right?
So then I fixed it. I I worked with
Bluehost at that time. I actually
transferred over to Shopify. And as it
was going ahead and learning all of this
stuff, that's when I started to actually
understand that concept. Another example
of this is now I'm trying to do more
in-person events. And in New York City
we did one and I was quite impatient.
The team knows this. When I have my
mindset to something, I'm like, I just
want to make it happen, no matter how
much money it costs me. And for me, I
want to make an impact in the in-person
community too, right? So, I went ahead
and was like, let's do it in New York.
And yeah, I didn't do so well in terms
of pricing or didn't do so well in terms
of how to get sponsors or I didn't know
about any of it. I just knew that I
wanted something that looked really cool
and left a really good impression on our
audience. So, I went ahead and did it
and I lost $37,000 or something like
that. And that's how I'm learning,
right? So, I'm learning in real time.
Then we hosted an event in London for
1,300 people. So, New York was 300
people. London was sold out, 1,300
people at the Troxy. We actually have
the vlog of this if we want to put it up
in the corner that you can go ahead and
watch. But, we sold that out. But, we
would have never learned that if we
didn't go through the New York process.
The way that I think about this is that
for the main learning event, the more I
can closely simulate the actual living
experience or in this case, I'm
literally doing the living experience,
the better I am for it. Something that
became a very good practice for me while
in college has turned into a very
productive habit while being a business
owner. And that is the next step. It is
called post-class immediate review or in
this case, I'm going to call this
flushing. Basically, at the very end of
the day, I'll have a notebook page
filled with all the most important
concepts that I've learned that day. I'm
really trying to consolidate the
information at that given period of
time. So, if there are practice
questions that I'm going through, as in,
did I really understand what the meeting
was about and can I in fact go ahead and
maybe build out another diagram so that
I can sure that I'm contextualizing
that, I certainly will because even if
it takes me 25, 35, even an hour long at
night, it is worth it because I'll
actually retain that information a lot
longer so that I'm not wasting time in
the future. But, I'm calling it flushing
because every other part of that
meeting, let's be honest, I am not going
to recall. This is actually quite
similar to even my biomedical
engineering days because if I was taking
eight classes maximum of credits each
term, there was no way that I was going
to recall every bit of information from
my thermodynamics class and then turn
around and remember everything from
computational modeling and then go into
calculus two and then also be able to
know how to do linear algebra by and
diffy Q and be like, I know every little
bit of detail. There's just no way. You
have to flush things that aren't of your
primary focus and that's okay. And so,
go ahead and delegate that to again a
repository second brain and really keep
the main thing the main thing. Then
finally, we have the revision staff.
This is my favorite, probably the most
fun and actually a lot of the team has
started to integrate this into their own
workflow. A really good example of this
to show you what I mean is my newest
storytelling content challenge. And so,
this is my very very very big weighted
launch that's happening quite soon. But
basically, while I was in France, I met
a lot of my followers.
Are you guys creators, too?
>> Yes.
>> Oh, you're kidding.
Oh, that's incredible. And one of them
recommended that I start a storytelling
content challenge to make a lot of my
teachings more accessible because the
VIP coaching that we have done has been
mostly focused on offerings that have
been $3,000 and up and this would be
significantly more affordable at a few
hundred dollars. And so, they thought,
all right, can you just do it in this
way where people can learn it along idea
where they'll do it themselves, but it's
a challenge format. And I was like, "Oh
my gosh, it's a phenomenal idea." What
was a vacation turned into a new
business and also ever since that for
last month, I haven't been sleeping and
trying to build out the best challenge I
can possibly develop. So basically, what
you see on this whiteboard is a diagram
of that storytelling content challenge.
I can't show all of it just yet. I will
eventually, but once we finalize
everything and we have all of our eyes
dotted and our tees crossed, we'll have
another video for What's crazy is that
that whiteboard with this diagram and
also all the steps that I now mentioned
before have been responsible for over
$13 million and over 35 team members
globally all in just 15 months at the
age of 25. I am telling you this because
you do not need to be the smartest
person in the room. You don't have to be
the most experienced. You don't have to
be somebody that has an actual gift for
it. You just don't. You need a system
and that's what I'm really good at
developing. Repeatable ones that allow
my success to be done over and over
again, but also it can transfer to you.
It can make it easy for you to take your
next step as well. If this is your first
time hearing about the four stage
system, you can go ahead and watch this
video where I break it all down. And if
you want to go ahead and learn how to
build a personal brand or business
utilizing this operating system, then
I'm going to be sharing that every
single week on this channel. I love all
of you, and I will see all of you at the
top.